

Oran, Algeria

□ (+213) 780489607 | ☑ rahmouni.abdelhak.1@gmail.com | 🔏 www.abdel7ak.xyz | 🖸 abdel7ak96 | 🛅 rahmouni-abdelhak

"The cave you fear to enter, holds the treasure you seek." Joseph Campbell

Summary

I am a software engineer with more than 2 years of full-time work experience. I currently work mainly with JavaScript/TypeScript in the Node.js ecosystem and MERN as my main stack. I started my career as a Full-Stack Developer, and I remain open to exploring and learning new tools. I have worked on multiple projects across web2 and web3 and collaborated with team members from around the world.

Work Experience ____

Intelifox Algiers, Algeria (Remote)

SENOIR FRONTEND DEVELOPER (FULL-TIME)

- February 2024 Present · Built and optimized reusable UI components, simplifying development workflows and enhancing scalability.
- · Improved chat functionality with new features like file sharing, message previews, and categorized channels, boosting user engagement.
- · Developed custom hooks to abstract complex data-fetching logic, improving code readability and performance for the development team. • Technical skills: React. js, TypeScript, Redux, RTK, styled-components, RESTful APIs, debugging, trouble-shooting.
- **Soft Skills:** Communication, documentation, time-management.

Shard Labs Zagreb, Croatia (Remote)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER (FULL-TIME)

March 2022 - February 2023

November 2021 - March 2022

August 2021 - September 2021

- · Actively managed and expanded the front-end functionalities of a crypto-staking solution on the Polygon Blockchain holding over 20 million dollars worth of customer assets.
- · Built and integrated the front-end of a crypto lending and borrowing protocol application on Aurora Blockchain.
- · Built and integrated the front-end of a Proof-Of-Attendance-Protocol application on the NEAR Blockchain, which successfully debuted at NEARCON and facilitated the minting of more than 1000 NFTs.
- · Conducted thorough code reviews, consistently ensuring adherence to clean-code best practices and maintaining codebase consistency.
- Technical skills: React.js, TypeScript, Next.js, Ethers.js, near-api-js, hardhat, TailwindCSS, styled-components, RESTful APIs, GraphQL, debug-
- Soft Skills: Communication, documentation, collaboration, planning.

Namla Cloud Paris, France (Remote)

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER (FULL-TIME)

- Spearheaded the development of a cloud orchestration & management platform.
- Thoroughly documented newly created components on Confluence.
- · Proactively embraced DevOps responsibilities to meet project deadlines and enhance my skill set.
- Implemented the company's inaugural website, driving its online presence and brand visibility
- Technical skills: TypeScript, React.js, Bootstrap, CSS, JSON, CI/CD, Docker, Gitlab, wireframing.
- **Soft Skills:** Communication, documentation, conceptualization.

Barsha Technology Gabes, Tunisia (Remote)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER (FREELANCE)

- · Developed a mobile app using Flutter to create a compliance checking tool for an offshore client.
- · Incorporated an engaging introduction slideshow to effectively showcase the step-by-step procedure.
- · Integrated slide animation to ensure smooth progression through each compliance checking step.
- Utilized the Google Sheets API as the backend to securely store and manage data.
- Technical skills: Flutter, Dart, Figma
- **Soft Skills:** Pressure-handling, communication, mockup, engaging presentation.

Skills

Programming TypeScript/JavaScript, Java, Python, PHP, C/C++, HTML5, CSS3, Dart, SQL.

Frameworks & libraries React, Next.js, Express, Node.js, Vue.js, GraphQL, Flutter, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Ethers.js.

Developer tools VSCode, Git, Docker, CI/CD, Testing.

Others LaTeX, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Figma, UI/UX Design.

Education

University of Science and Technology of Oran - Mohamed Boudiaf

Oran, Algeria

MASTER DEGREE IN INFORMATION & DATA SYSTEMS

Sept 2019 - Sept 2021

- **Coursework:** Operations research, Data analysis, Machine learning, Distributed systems, Cloud computing, Grid computing, Advanced databases, Ethics. Game theory, Multidimensional databases & data warehouses.
- Practical work: Hadoop, Spark, PL/SQL, Scala, Java Sockets, AndroidSDK, Python, PostgreSQL.

University of Science and Technology of Oran - Mohamed Boudiaf

Oran, Algeria

LICENCE DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sept 2016 - Juin 2019

- Coursework: Algebra, Calculus, Algorithms, Data structures, Web development, Mobile development, Object-oriented programming, Declarative programming, Logic programming, Assembly, Probabilities & statistics, Databases, Operating system, Networks, Graph theory, Cybersecurity, Compiler design.
- Practical work: C, C++, Java, Java Swing, HTML, CSS, PHP, Prolog, MIPS, SQL.

Extracurricular Activity

UDev (University Developers' Community)

Oran, Algeria

MEMBER & PRESIDENT

Jul 2017 - Aug 2021

- Voted second best speaker (out of 8) by the audience for delivering a talk at the community's annual conference about habit-forming technology.
- · Organized and conducted a comprehensive workshop on LaTeX specifically tailored for a group of 40 soon-to-be graduates.
- Efficiently reformed and refined the recruitment process, significantly reducing the need for human intervention.
- Exercised strategic leadership in formulating and implementing policies to optimize the community's public engagement.
- Actively involved in programs focused on entrepreneurship and competitive programming, fostering valuable skills and experiences.
- · Created a diverse range of original graphic materials for the community's social media and events.
- Technical Skills: Programming, technical writing, graphic design, community management.
- Soft Skills: Leadership, teaching, public speaking, collaboration, planning, team building.

Certifications

Sep 2024 Encode Club, EVM Bootcamp Q3 2024

May 2020 FreeCodeCamp, Responsive Web Design Certification

Mar 2020 FreeCodeCamp, JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification

Mar 2020 FreeCodeCamp, Front End Libraries Certification

Mar 2020 **Openclassroom**, Ultra fast applications using Node.js

Mar 2020 Openclassroom, Go Full-Stack With Node.js, Express, and MongoDB

Feb 2020 **Openclassroom**, Manage Your Code Project With Git & Github

Language proficiency _____

English, Fluent **French**, Advanced **Arabic**, Native